<?xml version ="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Root category="article">
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <title>More calm' Duterte appeals to governors to support war on drugs</title>
        <timePub>Jan 19 2017 06:09 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>A "more calm" President Rodrigo Duterte appealed to governors to help in the administration's campaign against illegal drugs, Philippine National Police Chief Director General Ronald "Bato" Dela Rosa said.
            "Mas kalmado at more on appeal, not more on threat na pakabaril ko kayo sa chief of police," Dela Rosa said of Duterte's hour-long meeting with the governors on Thursday.
            Just like the President's meeting with mayors, Dela Rosa said Duterte also cracked some jokes with the governors.
        Albay Governor Al Francis Bichara, national chairman of the League of Provinces of the Philippines, described the mood of the meeting as "friendly."</p><p>
            Bichara said Duterte did not mention any names of governors linked to illegal drugs and instead showed them a thick pile of papers, supposedly containing names of narco-politicians which will be handed over to the Department of the Interior and Local Government.
            "He really stressed his alarm. This drug thing is very disturbing to him, 
            especially with the magnitude and the numbers," Bichara said in a phone interview on ANC's "Top Story."
            Duterte also discussed federalism and denied state-sponsored extra judicial killings, according to Bichara.
        "The way I see it, he really wants to provide autonomous government especially to the Mindanao region," Bichara added.</p></body>
    </article>
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <title>Duterte: Drug addicts are worse than slaves</title>
        <timePub>Jan 19 2017 04:09 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>In yet another speech about the evils of illegal drug use, President Rodrigo Duterte compared drug addicts to slaves.
            "Ang kawawa nito, actually they are slaves. Mabuti pa ang slave, kasi kung mabili mo sa African market, magamit mo pa sa trabaho mo. Ito, they are slaves eternally to a chemical sponsored by a criminal, his pockets full of money at the expense of the Filipino," Duterte said during the oath-taking of officials of the Philippine National Police (PNP).
            In the same speech, Duterte also reprimanded the local officials involved in the illegal drug trade, once again showing a stack of paper with the names of the alleged narco-politicians.</p></body>
    </article>
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <author>Dharel Placido, ABS-CBN News</author>
        <title>Duterte curses Daanbantayan mayor during meeting</title>
        <timePub>Jan 19 2017 04:36 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>UNFORGIVABLE: President Rodrigo Duterte on Thursday revealed that he cursed a former police official he earlier tagged in the illegal drug trade.
            During a speech before high-ranking police officials in Malacañang, Duterte said he cursed former Chief Superintendent and now Daanbantayan, Cebu Mayor Vicente Loot during his meeting with mayors at the presidential palace last week.
            “Makita ko si Loot. Hindi ako nakapagpigil, minura ko. Sabi ko, ‘Mayor you are guilty of treason. You were once a police officer, inasahan ka ng gobyerno, ginastusan ka ng gobyerno tapos ganoon ang ginawa mo sa bayan?’” Duterte said.
            “Unforgivable yung ganon. I cannot reconcile how you can be so corrupt na pati ang kalaban mo ang mismong tao.”
            Loot is one of the five police officers identified by Duterte as allegedly involved in illegal drug trade.
            Loot was director of the Philippine National Police (PNP) Training Service and director of Police Regional Office 8 before retiring.
            He won as mayor of Daanbantayan, Cebu in the recently concluded May 9 elections.
            Loot has denied the accusation against him, claiming he is a victim of "black propaganda."</p></body>
    </article>
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <author>Trishia Billones, ABS-CBN News</author>
        <title>On martial law, Duterte can decide outside Constitution: Solgen</title>
        <timePub>Posted at Jan 19 2017 01:50 PM | Updated as of Jan 19 2017 03:47 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>
            (UPDATE) MANILA - The president may declare martial law outside the parameters set in the Constitution and even without approval from co-equal branches of government, under certain circumstances when people's welfare is on the line, the country's chief legal counsel claimed.
            Solicitor-general Jose Calida told reporters in Malacañang Thursday that President Rodrigo Duterte may declare martial law beyond reasons like invasion and rebellion, which are the only two provisions stated under the 1987 Constitution.
            "That is what is placed in the text book, but you know, there are certain situations as I said and these are hypothetical situations, when there is really a clear and present danger to our country, and nobody will help the President do his job as the father of the nation, he will not allow his family so to speak—us, Filipinos—to suffer because of the inability or unwillingness of certain functionaries to do what is right for the country," he said.
            To illustrate this "extra-constitutional" move which is consistent with the saying that the welfare of the people is the supreme law, Calida drew from the ouster of former President Ferdinand Marcos through street revolt.
            "In fact, during the 1986 EDSA revolution, if you notice, there was no martial law declared but there was a change in government. It was an extra-constitutional movement that changed the government. Why? Because probably during that time, there was really a need to do so," he said.
            "We cannot put the President in a box and tell him you can only do these things because the President cares for the country and if the country faces imminent danger and nobody is acting then, the welfare of the people is the supreme law," he added.
            But constitutionalist and former Commission on Elections chairman Christian Monsod maintains that Filipinos are still the final arbiter on the possible declaration of martial law.
            "The final arbiter are the sovereign people of the Philippines. And the sovereign people have spoken on their position with respect to declaration of martial law in the Constitution, section 18 of Article 7," he said in a phone interview on ANC.
            Monsod also advised the public not the be "overreactive" whenever Duterte or Malacañang officials discuss martial law.
            "Let’s look at the signs. Let’s look at what he (Duterte) wants to do with the constitution. I think we should not be overreactive to everything he and his minions say," he added.
            Over the weekend, Duterte said that he will declare martial law if the drug problem in the country worsens into something “virulent," but in a speech in Nueva Ecija Wednesday, he said he agrees with the military that there is no compelling reason yet to declare martial law.</p><p>But in the same speech Wednesday, Duterte again lamented the limits set by the Constitution on the declaration of martial law.
            Under the Constitution, congressional approval is needed if the imposition of martial law will exceed 60 days. Any citizen may also challenge the basis of the declaration of the martial law before the Supreme Court.
            Duterte reiterated, if this is the case, then the SC and Congress will most likely clash, since the legislative branch is usually allied with the executive.
            “Who decides now? Ang Supreme Court sabi huwag. Sabi ng Congress yes. Who decides? The sitting president. So, ako,” he said.</p></body> 
    </article>
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <author>Dharel Placido, ABS-CBN News</author>
        <title>Duterte to meet with SAF 44 widows</title>
        <timePub>Posted at Jan 19 2017 07:29 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>
            MANILA – President Rodrigo Duterte on Thursday said he will soon meet with the widows of slain Special Action Force (SAF) troopers who were killed in the January 2015 Mamasapano massacre.
            In a speech in Malacañang, Duterte revealed he would meet with the widows of the slain policemen. He insisted that the meeting should not be politicized.
            “I’ll meet the widows,” he said. “I’m not trying to scare anybody. I’m not trying to go into politics again.”
            The Mamasapano massacre dealt a serious blow to the credibility and popularity of Duterte’s predecessor, Benigno Aquino III, as the operation which led to the deaths of 44 elite policemen was carried out allegedly under the orders of a suspended police chief.
            The suspended police chief was Alan Purisima, who is known for his closeness to Aquino.
            The main target of the anti-terror raid, Zulkifli bin Hir alias Marwan, was killed, but at the expense of the 44 cops who clashed with private armed groups, the Bangsamoro Islamic Freedom Fighters (BIFF), and even the Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF), which at the time was at the height of peace negotiations with the government.
            Duterte once toyed with the possibility of ordering a reopening of the investigation into the massacre. He particularly wanted to know what happened to the $5 million bounty that the United States offered for Marwan’s arrest.
            In his speech, Duterte said he was no longer interested to know what happened to the reward. He said what was bugging him was why air assets from certain parts of Mindanao were not deployed at the time of the clashes.
            “I don’t want to bring this up but there are still disturbing issues surrounding Mamasapano. I only have one question for all.
            “I’m not trying to revive or revisit the issue, but what’s bugging me is… why was it there was a war the whole day at hindi pinapasok ang sa Awang, Davao City, General Santos. Bakit hindi tinawag ang air assets?” Duterte said.</p></body> 
    </article>
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <title>'Political genius' Duterte can't be put in a box: Solgen Calida</title>
        <timePub>Posted at Jan 19 2017 06:39 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>
           President Rodrigo Duterte is a "political genius" who may sometimes be misinterpreted and who can not be "put in a box," Solicitor-General Jose Calida said Thursday.
            Calida described Duterte as such after a reporter asked if Duterte's latest pronouncements regarding martial law may have been intended to bring out the loopholes in the 1987 Constitution to the public's knowledge and urge that these be amended. He admitted, this is "a possibility."
            "Actually, as I said earlier, the president is a political genius. Sometimes, his statements are so deep that you may misinterpret what he’s really saying," he said.
            "But you know, somebody said the mouth is a weapon of mass destruction, so probably he’s just messaging it so that people will get the idea and agree with him," he said.
            Calida then highlighted that the maverick leader had been criticized "as being not a polished diplomat," but he was able to raise P1 trillion in official development assistance (ODA).
            "Do you know of any previous presidents who did that? By mouthing those who criticized our president and insulted him and the sovereignty of the Filipino people?," he said.
            "He’s a maverick and you cannot put him in a box, but we should just the result of what he is saying," he added.</p></body> 
    </article>
        <article source="ABSCBN">
        <author>Dharel Placido, ABS-CBN News</author>
        <title>Duterte names another elected official in narco-list</title>
        <timePub>Posted at Jan 19 2017 05:32 PM | Updated as of Jan 19 2017 06:12 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>
           MANILA – President Rodrigo Duterte on Thursday named another elected official in his so-called “narco-list.”
            During a speech in front of high-ranking police official in Malacañang, Duterte read the name of Licerio Antiporada. He said Antiporada was included under the category “elected officials” in Region 2 (Cagayan Valley) in his narco-list.
            “Barangay captain siguro ito. Bigtime pusher, member, Antiporada-Prado Drug Group,” Duterte said.
            Duterte has repeatedly threatened barangay officials in the country for their alleged involvement in the illegal drug trade.
            He told police officials that nearly 40 percent of barangay officials in the country have links to drugs. 
            The president met with mayors from around the country last week. He also had a meeting with governors today.
            In a speech last Saturday, Duterte recalled how he confronted the mayors over the country’s drug problem.
            “Baka akala ninyo nagbobolahan tayo dito. I called the mayors in the Philippines, ni-lockdown ko. Kung sabihin ko sa inyo, ‘i-lockdown din dito. Sarahan mo ‘yan diyan mga sundalo…’ Para walang magtsismis,” Duterte said in his Saturday speech in Davao City.
            “Sinabi ko talaga sa kanila, totoo iyon and I said, pardon my language because very may mga…’P**** i** ninyo!’”
            He also said that he would ask governors to exercise their supervisory powers over local officials, even as he threatened to order an ambush or poisoning of officials linked to the drug trade.
            “Sinabi ko talaga. And I’d be calling the governors sa next week. Sabihin ko talaga sa kanila. You tell your barangay captains, may     supervisory powers kayo and ‘yung mga cities under you, ‘yung hindi pa charter cities, you tell the mayors, reiterate to them,” Duterte said.
            “But I would like to tell you, hindi ko kaya lecturan lahat ng ano…Huwag ka gyud magkumpiyansa sa akin, p***** i**, papatayin talaga kita. Believe me. Hahanapan kita ng ambush, lasunin kita.”</p></body> 
    </article>
    <article source="ABSCBN">
        <title>PH sells $2B in bonds, showing confidence in Duterte: treasurer</title>
        <timePub>Posted at Jan 19 2017 03:52 PM | Updated as of Jan 19 2017 04:43 PM</timePub>
        <body><p>
           MANILA – The Philippines has sold $2 billion in dollar-denominated bonds despite volatility in the global market, highlighting investor confidence in the economy and the new government of President Rodrigo Duterte, the country’s treasurer said Thursday.
            The 25-year securities, which were priced at par to yield 3.7 percent, were oversubscribed, National Treasurer Roberto Tan told ANC’s “Market Edge with Cathy Yang.”
            Manila will “look into” a possible yuan bond issue next year, Tan said, adding the foreign component of this year’s borrowing program was finished.
            “This is an achievement that we can be proud of, particularly now that we are under new leadership, showing the confidence of the international investor market on the economy as well as the new administration,” Tan said.
            “For emerging markets, the Philippines stands out as one of the favorites,” he said.
            It was Philippines' the first foreign debt issue under Duterte, who assumed office in June last year with the promise to fight crime and corruption.
            The economy grew 7.1 percent in the third quarter last year, Duterte’s first three months in office. The pace maintained the Philippines’ status as one of the world’s fastest-growing economies.
            Asked about yuan-denominated debt or “panda bonds,” Tan said: “We will probably look inot that but it might be sometime after this year. We have not programmed a panda bond issuance this year.</p></body> 
    </article>
    <article source="Inquirer">
        <author>By: Marlon Ramos - Reporter </author>
        <title>Duterte dines with tycoons</title>
        <timePub>05:50 AM January 19, 2017</timePub>
        <body><p>
           HANOI— President Rodrigo Duterte has received reports that the Central Intelligence Agency wants him dead.
            He made the remarks in his speech before hundreds of Vietnam-based Filipinos on Wednesday night at the Intercontinental Hotel.
            “Sabi nila. pa-plano-plano raw ang CIA na patayin ako. Susmaryosep, ginoo,” he said in his hour-long, rambling speech</p>
            <p>He was then discussing how he would not go to war against China over the territorial dispute in the South China Sea.
                In the same speech, Duterte promised to end the Philippines’ joint military exercises with the United States.</p>
            <p>Early this week, he also claimed that the U.S. disliked him.
                Prior to mentioning the alleged threat from the American intelligence agency, the President said he will not abandon the 
                arbitral tribunal’s ruling which favored the Philippines’ claims over the West Philippine Sea.
                “There will always be a time to reckon the thing with. When that time comes, sabihin ko sa China, ‘ito ‘yung amin. I will talk 
                to you but I will not go out of the four corners of this paper.’ Pero it is not the time to die,” he said</p>
            <p>Duterte then added that he will not send his soldiers to war and be massacred in a battleground like Palawan.
                “Naloko na. Eh kung dalhin natin doon sa San Francisco OK ako. Oo, ‘yung China, mamili kayo diyan. Pero mag-away tayo tapos 
                gawin mong battleground eh paalisin ko kayo, pati ang America, ‘umalis ka diyan,'” he said.
                He then claimed receiving reports that the CIA wants him dead.
                Duterte then joked that he would ask the intelligence agency to give him more time to get used to being the Philippine 
                president.
                “Until now I cannot even believe that I am the mayor. Bigyan mo muna ako ng panahon mag-isip bilang presidente,” he said 
                before jumping to another topic. TVJ
            </p>
        </body>     
</article>
    <article source="GMA">
        <author>TRISHA MACAS, GMA News </author>
        <title>Duterte in Hanoi: I heard CIA out to kill me</title>
        <timePub>Published September 29, 2016 4:22pm</timePub>
        <body><p>
           President Rodrigo Duterte said he had received reports that the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) wants him dead.
            Duterte made the remarks in a speech before the Filipino community in Hanoi on Wednesday night.
            “Sabi nila pa-plano-plano raw ang CIA na patayin ako. Susmaryosep, ginoo," Duterte said with a straight face while discussing how 
            he would not 
            allow a war with China over disputed waters in the South China Sea.
            Duterte on Wednesday night also said that the Philippines' joint military exercises with the US in October will be the last under 
            his   
            administration.</p>
            <p>While saying that he would honor the Philippines' treaty obligations with the country's most influential ally and the world's
                only remaining superpower, Duterte in another speech indicated that he was opening lines with Russia and China
                Before briefly mentioning the alleged threat from the US' intelligence agency, Duterte said he would not abandon the favorable 
                ruling made by the Permanent Court of Arbitration in the Philippines' case against China's excessive claims in the South China 
                Sea.
                However, he added that it was not the time to confront China's military with the tribunal's ruling especially if the 
                battleground will be in 
                the archipelago.
            "I am not ready to commit the soldiers of this country just to be massacred and besides—besides t— ina, ang battleground, ang 
            Palawan? Naloko na," Duterte said.</p>
            <p>"Eh kung dalhin natin doon sa San Francisco okay ako. [laughter]  Oo, ‘yung China, mamili kayo diyan," he added.
                “Hindi natin kaya ang China so sabi ko—even with the help of America. So we talk,” Duterte said.
                In jest, he then asked the CIA to give him more time to get used to being a President.
                “Bigyan mo muna ako ng panahon mag-isip [bilang] Presidente," Duterte said before moving on to another topic.
                On Monday, the president claimed that the US disliked him, the same way it disliked Saddam Hussein of Iraq, Muammar Gaddafi of 
                Libya, and Bashar al-Assad of Syria.
            </p></body>     
</article>
  <article source="GMA">
        <author>TRISHA MACAS, GMA News </author>
        <title>Duterte: Only poor use shabu, rich addicts do 'safer' cocaine, heroin</title>
        <timePub>Published August 24, 2016 7:18pm</timePub>
        <body><p>
           Why is the government's campaign against illegal drugs focused on suspects in urban poor communities?
            Aside from saying that wealthy drug lords are running their illicit business from outside the country, President Rodrigo Duterte 
            said there's 
            no shabu trade in exclusive villages like Forbes Park in Makati City.
            "Wala akong nakitang nag-distribute diyan sa Forbes Park, nagbabantay din ako, kasi ang mga tao diyan hindi shabu ang hinihirit 
            diyan. Ang mga  
            tao diyan hinihirit ay cocaine pati heroin," Duterte said in a news conference, held at the wake of Senior Inspector Mark Garcia.
            Garcia died in a buy bust operation in Antipolo over the weekend.
            "But cocaine and heroin are not as destructive as shabu because itong cocaine and heroin are manufactured out of the derivatives 
            of a poppy, 
            tanim iyan parang marijuana. So it is not as destructive to the mind as meth, which is just really a combination of a deadly mix 
            of chemicals," Duterte said.
            Duterte said the poor mostly use shabu or methamphetamine hydrochloride, which is sold in not so well-off communities.
            "Mahihirap ang marami kasi they are an easy target," Duterte said.
            On criticisms that his war on drugs was anti-poor, Duterte said campaign exempted no one.
            "Just because you are poor, you are excused from apprehension...? Rich or poor, I do not give a shit," Duterte said.  
            "My order is to destroy," he added. —NB/JST, GMA News
            </p></body>     
</article>
    <article source="GMA">
        <title>Duterte willing to unleash a Hitler on PHL criminals</title>
        <timePub>Published September 30, 2016 2:53am</timePub>
        <body><p>
           President Rodrigo Duterte on Friday indicated that he was willing to do what Hitler did to the Jews to the country's criminals.
            "Hitler massacred three million Jews. Now, there are three million drug addicts... I'd be happy to slaughter them," Duterte said 
            upon his arrival in Davao City from an official visit to Vietnam.
            "At least if Germany had Hitler, the Philippines would have… You know my victims, I would like to be, all criminals, to finish  
            the problem of my country and save the next generation from perdition," he added.
            Duterte made the remarks as he once again addressed the criticisms he had been getting from the United States and the European 
            Union for 
            killings attributed to his war on drugs.
            "Kayong US, EU, you can call me anything but I was never into or I am never into hypocrisy like you," Duterte said.
            "You close your doors. It's winter time. There are migrants escaping from the Middle East. You allow them to rot and the you're 
            worried about 
            the deaths of about one thousand, or two thousand, or three thousand?" he added in apparent reference to the refusal of some 
            countries to allow Syrian refugees into their territories.
            According to official police data, more than 3,000 people have been killed in drug-related incidents since Duterte assumed office.
            But while he has repeatedly denied having a hand in summary killings, Duterte has not backed off from his tough talk, often 
            repeating that 
            there is no law preventing him from threatening criminals. --NB, GMA News
            </p></body>     
</article>
     <article source="GMA">
        <title>Duterte: I'm about 'to cross the Rubicon' with the United States</title>
        <timePub>September 26, 2016 5:28pm</timePub>
        <body><p>
          President Rodrigo Duterte on Monday hinted that he's about to go past a point of no return in terms of the Philippines' relationship 
            with the United States, revealing that he had sought help from Russia about the matter.
            "I'm about to cross the Rubicon between me and the United States. At least for the next six years. I would need your help," he 
            said, referring to his meeting earlier this month with Russian Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev at the sidelines of the Association 
            of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) Summit.
            The Philippines and the US are treaty allies, having signed a mutual defense treaty in 1951 and a visiting forces agreement in 
            1998. The US is also the Philippines' biggest foreign investor and the country's second biggest export market next to Japan.    
            But the relationship has been frayed under Duterte, who has bristled at criticism about the rising death toll of his 
            administration's drug war from the US and other institutions such as the United Nations and the European Union. He has repeatedly 
            expressed his desire to rid Mindanao of American troops supposedly to pursue peace talks, while declaring earlier this month that 
            he wanted to stop joint patrols with the US in the South China Sea amid a maritime dispute with Beijing.
            Duterte, meanwhile, has expressed openness to welcome more investments from China and Russia. He has also raised the possibility 
            of buying arms from the two nations.
            Meanwhile, with trips to China and Japan also in the works, Duterte bared plans to visit Russia.
            “After China, I think I’ll go to Japan and I’ll go to Russia,” Duterte said during his press conference after the oath-taking of 
            the officers of the Malacanang press groups.
            'US doesn't like me'
            When asked to clarify his statement, Duterte noted that United States needed to get the Congress' approval before its President 
            can declare war to help an ally.
            "There is a RP-US Pact that was in the ‘50s. It says that an attack on the Philippines would be an attack of the United States," 
            Duterte said.
            "But in the United States Constitution, it says that before a President can declare war, with anybody in defense of an ally, he 
            has to Congress for permission to go to war. That’s the problem. So if Congress will not give him that authority, what will happen 
            to us?"
            Duterte said he is aware that the United States did not like him, comparing himself to deposed leaders such as Iraq’s Saddam 
            Hussein, Libya’s Muammar Gaddafi, and Syria’s Bashar al-Assad.
            “Iraq, Libya, Syria. It’s in turmoil, every day bomba nang bomba. Ano’ng gusto ninyo? Ayaw na ninyo kay Saddam. Ayaw na ninyo kay 
            Gaddafi. Ayaw ninyo kay Assad. That’s the problem. Ayaw ninyo ako, tapos idale ninyo ang buong Pilipinas,” Duterte said.
            In the same press conference, Duterte said he didn't have any plans to junk alliances.
            "I am not really going to break ties but we are opening alliances with China," he said. 
            </p></body>     
</article>
    <article source="GMA">
        <author>TRISHA MACAS</author>
        <title>Duterte declares break from US in military, economics</title>
        <timePub>September 26, 2016 5:28pm</timePub>
        <body><p>
          BEIJING — President Rodrigo Duterte on Wednesday declared that he was breaking the Philippines' military and economic alliance with 
            the United States, the country's longtime ally.
            Duterte made the remark before Chinese government officials and business leaders who attended the Philippines-China Trade and 
            Investment Forum.
            With the "separation" from the US, Duterte said he would now be relying on the Chinese officials and businessmen.
            "I announce my separation from the United States both in the military but economics also. So please you have another problem of 
            economics in my country," Duterte said.
            "I have separated from them so I will be dependent on you for a long time but don't worry we will also help," he added.
            Duterte said he also planned to visit Russia and firm up ties with Moscow.
            "I realign myself in your ideological flow and maybe I will also go to Russia to talk to Putin. There are three of us against the 
            world. China, Philippines, Russia," Duterte said.
            Duterte over the past months stepped up his anti-US rhetoric after US officials, including US President Barack Obama expressed 
            concern over the alleged extrajudicial killings blamed on his war on drugs.
            The President also announced that October's joint military exercises with the US would be the last under his term.
            $13.5 billion
            Duterte made his comments in China, where he is visiting with at least 200 business people to pave the way for what he calls a new 
            commercial alliance as relations with longtime ally US deteriorate.
            His trade secretary, Ramon Lopez, said $13.5 billion in deals would be signed
            Duterte's efforts to engage China, months after a tribunal ruling in the Hague over South China Sea disputes in favor of the 
            Philippines, marks a reversal in foreign policy since the 71-year-old former mayor took office on June 30.
            China has pulled out all the stops to welcome Duterte, including a marching band complete with batton-twirling band master at his 
            official welcoming ceremony outside the Great Hall of the People, which most leaders do not get.
            President Xi Jinping, meeting Duterte earlier in the day, called the visit a "milestone" in ties.
            Xi told Duterte that China and the Philippines were brothers and they could "appropriately handle disputes", though he did not 
            mention the South China Sea in remarks made in front of reporters.
            "I hope we can follow the wishes of the people and use this visit as an opportunity to push China-Philippines relations back on a 
            friendly footing and fully improve things," Xi said.
            Following their meeting, during which Duterte said relations with China had entered a new "springtime", Chinese vice foreign 
            minister Liu Zhenmin said the South China Sea issue was not the sum total of relations.
            "The two sides agreed that they will do what they agreed five years ago, that is to pursue bilateral dialogue and consultation in 
            seeking a proper settlement of the South China Sea issue," Liu said.
            China claims most of the energy-rich South China Sea through which about $5 trillion in ship-borne trade passes every year. 
            Neighbors Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Taiwan and Vietnam also have claims.
            In 2012, China seized the disputed Scarborough Shoal and denied Philippine fishermen access to its fishing grounds.
            Liu said the shoal was not mentioned and he did not answer a question about whether Philippine fishermen would be allowed there. 
            He said both countries had agreed on coastguard and fisheries cooperation, but did not give details.
            Sea row takes backseat
            Duterte's tone toward Beijing is in contrast to the language he has used against the United States, after being infuriated by U.S. 
            criticism of his bloody war on drugs.
            On Wednesday, to the cheers of hundreds of Filipinos in Beijing, Duterte said Philippine foreign policy was veering towards China.
            "I will not go to America anymore. We will just be insulted there," Duterte said. "So time to say goodbye my friend."
            Duterte had said the South China Sea arbitration case would "take the back seat" during talks, and that he would wait for the 
            Chinese to bring up the issue rather than doing so himself.
            Xi said issues that could not be immediately be resolved should be set aside, according to the Chinese foreign ministry.
            China has welcomed the Philippines approaches, even as Duterte has vowed not to surrender any sovereignty to Beijing, which views 
            the South China Sea Hague ruling as null and void.
            China has also expressed support for his drug war, which has raised concern in Western capitals about extrajudicial killing.
            Duterte's overtures to China have been accompanied by signs of improving business ties with the world's second largest economy.
            China's Liu said Beijing will restore Philippine agricultural exports to China and provide financing for Philippine 
            infrastructure.
            </p></body>     
</article>
     <article source="GMA">
        <title>Duterte says 'goodbye' to US ties in Beijing </title>
        <timePub>Published August 24, 2016 7:18pm</timePub>
        <body><p>
           Why is the government's campaign against illegal drugs focused on suspects in urban poor communities?
            Aside from saying that wealthy drug lords are running their illicit business from outside the country, President Rodrigo Duterte 
            said there's 
            no shabu trade in exclusive villages like Forbes Park in Makati City.
            "Wala akong nakitang nag-distribute diyan sa Forbes Park, nagbabantay din ako, kasi ang mga tao diyan hindi shabu ang hinihirit 
            diyan. Ang mga  
            tao diyan hinihirit ay cocaine pati heroin," Duterte said in a news conference, held at the wake of Senior Inspector Mark Garcia.
            Garcia died in a buy bust operation in Antipolo over the weekend.
            "But cocaine and heroin are not as destructive as shabu because itong cocaine and heroin are manufactured out of the derivatives 
            of a poppy, 
            tanim iyan parang marijuana. So it is not as destructive to the mind as meth, which is just really a combination of a deadly mix 
            of chemicals," Duterte said.
            Duterte said the poor mostly use shabu or methamphetamine hydrochloride, which is sold in not so well-off communities.
            "Mahihirap ang marami kasi they are an easy target," Duterte said.
            On criticisms that his war on drugs was anti-poor, Duterte said campaign exempted no one.
            "Just because you are poor, you are excused from apprehension...? Rich or poor, I do not give a shit," Duterte said.  
            "My order is to destroy," he added. —NB/JST, GMA News
            </p></body>     
</article>
</Root>
